Guide to the National Humanities Institute, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
National Humanities Institute, Yale University, records
1974-1979
RU 559
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.25
(12 boxes)
The records consist of program proposals, correspondence, memoranda, film, annual reports, financial statements, and papers documenting the National Humanities Institute at Yale University.
National Humanities Institute
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutions, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject and record type.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of program proposals, correspondence, memoranda, film, annual reports, financial statements, and papers documenting the National Humanities Institute at Yale University.
Humanities -- Study and teaching; Research institutes; National Humanities Institute
- Records, circa 1974-1979; Accession 19ND-A-158
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2013
  - Fellows, 1975-1976
    - Assorted course syllabi, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - S.S. pending business correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Evaluations, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - NHI related activities, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - notices/memos, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - printed distributions, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - stipends, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - relocation, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Syllabi, exams, bibliographies for courses of K. Sklar, UCLA (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Readings in the Social History of American Women,'' compiled by K. Sklar, UCLA (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Master List, 1975-1976: correspondence A-H (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Master List, 1975-1976: correspondence K-Z (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Master List, 1975-1976: official (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Master List, 1975-1976: preliminary (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Biographies of candidates for fellowship, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - NHI, Senior Fellows (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Nominated Fellows, 1975-1976: lists, preliminary (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Nominated Fellows, 1975-1976: preliminary correspondence respondence (by institution) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Fellows, 1976-1977
    - Assorted course syllabi (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Staff/calendar (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Fellows, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Evaluations, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - commencement (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - notices/rnemos (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - printed distributions (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - regional visits (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Master List, 1976-1977: correspondence (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Nominations 1976-1977: lists (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Nominations 1976-1977: preliminary correspondence (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Fellows, 1977-1978
    - Assorted course syllabi (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Collegial seminars (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Evaluations (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Interest groups (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Fellows: general (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Fellows: notices/memos (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Fellows: printed distributions (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Seminars (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Invited: Janson, Horst/Peter (MU) (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Invited: Knoll, Robert E. (U. of Nebraska) (Box 5, Folder 87)
    - Invited: Wellek, Nonna (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Invited: Woodard, Calvin (U. of Va. Law School) (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Master List 1977-1978: correspondence (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Solicitations 1977-1978: Community Colleges (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Office Files
    - Administration, general, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Administration, general, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Administration, general, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Calendars: NHI, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Calendars: NHI, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Calendars: NHI, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Consultants (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Housing (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Internal Revenue Service, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - (YU) Library (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Publicity (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Space (53 Wall St.) (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Advisory Committee I (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Advisory Committee II (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Advisory Committee III (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Advisory Council: general, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Advisory Council: general, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Advisory Council: general, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Advisory Council
      - Ambrosioso (Box 6, Folder 116)
      - Billington (Box 6, Folder 117)
      - Bonham (Box 6, Folder 118)
      - Brackett (Box 6, Folder 119)
      - Colton (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - Conway (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - See also: Executive Board (Box 6, Folder 122)
      - Fisher (Box 6, Folder 123)
      - Furniss (Box 6, Folder 124)
      - Goetzmann (Box 6, Folder 125)
      - Gulick (Box 6, Folder 126)
      - Iselin (Box 6, Folder 127)
      - Liebmann (Box 6, Folder 128)
      - Lindzeg (Box 6, Folder 129)
      - McMurrin (Box 6, Folder 130)
      - Noyes (Box 6, Folder 131)
      - Ray (Box 6, Folder 132)
      - Sawyer (Box 6, Folder 133)
      - Skothaim (Box 6, Folder 134)
      - White (Box 6, Folder 135)
      - See: Executive Board (Box 6, Folder 136)
      - Berman (Box 6, Folder 137)
      - Holmberg (Box 6, Folder 138)
      - Sullivan (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - Special Programs: American Studies (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Special Programs: British Studies (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Special Programs: Council for Religion in Independent Schools (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Connecticut Humanities Council (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Council on the Humanities/Yale (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Media Design Studio (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Special Programs: NEH Seminar (Butts) (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Special Programs: The National Humanities Faculty (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - UNESCO (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Seven Springs: general (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Fellows Conference, 1977 May 22-27 (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Fellows Conference, 1976 May 23-26 (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Fellows Conference, 1975 May 2-4 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Fellows (Invited) Conference, 1975 April 2-6 (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - NHI Humanities Conference, 1978 April 29 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - NHI Humanities Conference, 1977 April 30 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - NHI Humanities Conference, 1976 May 1 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - NHI correspondence: general, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - NHI correspondence: general, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Chicago, NHI at (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Humanities Institutes Panel: Prof Mack, 1976 April 9 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - NHI, Phase II: committee (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Visitors, Institute, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Visitors, Institute, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Assorted loose correspondence (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Annual report, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Annual report, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Annual report, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - Quarterly reports, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 169)
    - Quarterly reports, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Quarterly reports, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Grant: substantive EN-20798-74-372, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Grant: substantive EN-20798-74-372, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - Grant: substantive EN-20798-74-372, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Grant: substantive EN-20798-74-372, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Grant: proposal EN-20798-74-372 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Fiscal: budgets, grant (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Fiscal: inventories, equipment (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Fiscal: statements 44537 (contract), 1979 January-March (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1978 July-1979 February (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1978 January-June (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1977 July-December (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Coffee and accounts, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1977 January-June (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1976 July-December (Box 9, Folder 185)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1976 January-June (Box 9, Folder 186)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1975 July-December (Box 9, Folder 187)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1975 January-June (Box 9, Folder 188)
    - Fiscal: 66803, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 189)
    - Fiscal: statements 00001, 1974-76 (Box 9, Folder 190)
    - Fiscal: statements 44805, 1974 June-December (Box 9, Folder 191)
    - Executive Board
      - General, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 192)
      - General, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 193)
      - Ballots (Box 10, Folder 194)
      - General, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 195)
      - General, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 196)
      - Coles (Box 10, Folder 197)
      - Conway (Box 10, Folder 198)
      - deMan (Box 10, Folder 199)
      - Giamatti (Box 10, Folder 200)
      - Goetzmann (Box 10, Folder 201)
      - Gray (Box 10, Folder 202)
      - Pelikan (Box 10, Folder 203)
      - Pelligrino (Box 10, Folder 204)
      - Brown (Box 10, Folder 205)
      - Scott (Box 10, Folder 206)
      - Silber (Box 10, Folder 207)
      - White (Box 10, Folder 208)
      - Black (Box 10, Folder 209)
      - Brown (Box 10, Folder 210)
      - Demetz (Box 10, Folder 211)
      - Fisher (Box 10, Folder 212)
      - Hartman (Box 10, Folder 213)
      - McClelIan (Box 10, Folder 214)
      - Morgan (Box 10, Folder 215)
    - Foster Foundation: substantive --66803 (Box 10, Folder 216)
    - Executive Board, 1977 May 1 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - Executive Board, 1976 October 31 (Box 10, Folder 218)
    - Executive Board, 1976 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 219)
    - Executive Board, 1976 January 16 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - Executive Board, 1975 October 31 (Box 10, Folder 221)
    - Executive Board, 1975 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 222)
    - Executive Board, 1975 April 4 (Box 10, Folder 223)
    - Executive Board, 1975 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 224)
    - Executive Board (cancelled), 1975 January 31 (Box 10, Folder 225)
    - Executive Board, 1974 December 6 (Box 10, Folder 226)
    - Executive Board, 1974 November 8 (Box 10, Folder 227)
    - Executive Board, 1974 September 30 (Box 10, Folder 228)
    - Advisory Council, 1976 October 30 (Box 10, Folder 229)
    - Advisory Council, 1976 May 2 (Box 10, Folder 230)
    - Advisory Council, 1975 November 1 (Box 10, Folder 231)
    - Faculty correspondence: Smith, John E. (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Faculty correspondence: Mack, M. (Box 10, Folder 233)
    - Close-down period, 1978 July-1979 March 31 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Close-down period, 1978 January 1-June 30 (Box 10, Folder 235)
    - Correspondence - Chronological
      - 1977 Jul 1-Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 236)
      - 1977 Jan 1-Jun 30 (Box 10, Folder 237)
      - 1976 Jul-Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 238)
      - 1976 Jan 1-Jun 30 (Box 10, Folder 239)
      - 1975 Jul 1-Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 240)
      - 1975 May 1-Jun 30 (Box 10, Folder 241)
      - 1975 Mar 1-Apr 30 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - 1975 Jan 1-Feb 28 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - 1974 Nov 1-Dec 31 (Box 10, Folder 244)
      - 1974 Sep 1-Oct 31 (Box 10, Folder 245)
      - 1974 Jun 1-Aug 30 (Box 10, Folder 246)
    - Assorted papers and newsletters (Box 11, Folder 247)
    - Brochure, National Humanities Institute (Box 11, Folder 248)
    - National Humanities Institute: Its History (Box 11, Folder 249)
    - National Humanities Institute: Planning papers (Box 11, Folder 250)
    - Brochure (Box 11, Folder 251)
    - Committee on Future (Box 11, Folder 252)
    - Phase 2: active (Box 11, Folder 253)
    - Collegial Seminar (Box 11, Folder 255)
    - Fellows Courses, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 256)
    - NHI: the proposal and reactions (Box 11, Folder 257)
    - Unlabelled folder (faculty of other colleges (?)) (Box 11, Folder 258)
    - NHI: publicity and aims (Box 11, Folder 259)
    - NEH Humanities Institute: the topic (Box 11, Folder 260)
  - Visiting Fellows, Final Papers, and General Files
    - Unidentified correspondence (Box 12, Folder 261 - 262)
    - Fisiting Fellows: general, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 265)
    - Chambers/Dixon, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 272)
    - Welty, Eudora, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 284)
    - Pope-Hennessy, Sir John, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 286)
    - Rawls, John, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 287)
    - Visiting Fellows: general, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 289)
    - Visitors: seminar, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 290)
    - Greeley, Rev. Andrew, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 296)
    - Momaday, Scott, 1975-1976; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 12)
    - Slotkin, Richard, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 302)
    - General files (Box 12, Folder 304)
    - Final papers (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - National Humanities Institute Series - 12 audiotapes (reel-to-reel)
    - Peter Berger: "Mediating Structures and National Policy: Family, Church, Neighborhood and Voluntary Associations", 1975 December 15; 1 (Box 12)
    - Leon Edel: "Nature of Psychological Evidence", 1976 January 12; 2 (Box 12)
    - Anthony Garvan: "American Studies and the New Humanities", 1976 February 2; 1 (Box 12)
    - Robert Heilbroner: "The Decline of Business Civilization", 1976 February 9; 1 (Box 12)
    - N. Scott Momaday: "In Wonder and Delight: Indian Oral Tradition", 1976 February 23; 1 (Box 12)
    - E. P. Thompson: "The Sale of Wives in England in the 18th and 19th Centuries", 1976 March 22; 1 (Box 12)
    - Garry Wills: "Jefferson Through Lincoln's Eyes", 1976 March 29; 1 (Box 12)
    - Erich Heller: "Psychoanalysis and the Misinterpretation of Literature", 1977 April 18; 1 (Box 12)
    - James Ackerman: "Judgments of Value: Reflections on Art and History", 1977 December 12; 1 (Box 12)